Daniel Cucinotta

Fair Lawn, NJ

cucinotta.daniel024@gmail.com

973-910-1715







SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Data Specialist / Analyst for various types of data systems as well as Full-Stack Web Developer with more than 4 years of educational experience in designing, implementing, and managing secure data systems, including mapping / configuring networks / routing. Ambitious and focused with the dexterity to perform a vast range of tasks apropos data scraping operations for producing unique datasets as well as clean, standardize, merge, and explore data. Additionally, the aptitude to execute statistical functions, generate various types of machine learning models as well as descriptive analytics models to produce a variety of visualizations and comprehensive reports. Adept, versatile, and resourceful with numerous programming languages, software, and platforms for building aesthetically appealing responsive websites with HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Possess excellent written / verbal communication and leadership skills as well as the capacity to conduct work independently and / or collaboratively.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University

Durham, NC

Bachelor of Science: Data Management / Data Analytics

April 2024

- GPA: 3.0 / 3.0
- Data science / analytics procedures and tools using Excel, Jupyter Notebook (Python and R), as well as Tableau.
- Data / information management and governance.
- Project management and IT leadership roles as well as IT business practices.

Pitt Community College

Winterville, NC

Associate in Applied Science: Computer Programming and Development

June 2018 - December 2021 June 2018 - December 2021

Associate in Arts

- GPA: 4.0 / 4.0 (cumulative dual degree)
- Programming with SQL, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C++, and JAVA.
- Design, implement, and deploy databases as well as networks and security with Linux, CISCO, and Oracle.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: SQL, Python, R, JavaScript / JSON / jQuery / Express / Angular / node, C++, Java, HTML5, and CSS / SCSS.
- Operating Systems: Linux (Bash) And Windows (PowerShell).
- Software: pgAdmin4, SQL Server (SSMS), MS Office, Adobe CS5, Tableau, Power BI, Anaconda (Pandas and Tidyverse), Knime, and Wireshark.
- Databases: Excel, PostgreSQL, MS SQL, Oracle, MySQL, and NoSQL (MongoDB).
- Platforms: Git/GitHub/Github.io, Google API's, Docker, and Heroku.
- IDEs: VSCode, Jupyter Notebook, PyCharm, WebStorm, Dreamweaver, Code::Blocks, and SQL Developer.
- **Data Scraping**: Python (Beautiful Soup), and R (rvest).

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Bachelor's Capstone April 2024

Analyzed World Data Analyst Jobs and Salaries 2020 – 2023 by merging, cleaning, and standardizing 5 datasets
as well as produced an illustrated presentation of several dashboards in a story with Tableau. A comprehensive
report outlining the datasets, processes, and analyses was assembled to convey the information gleaned from the
visual models as well as the statistical significance and fit of testing the data models.

Website Developer

Portfolio 😇

May 2024

Designed / deployed a responsive website by employing JavaScript / JSON / jQuery, CSS / SCSS, and HTML. A
portfolio showcasing projects and accomplishments was developed to demonstrate proficiency as well as the
inclusion of a profile section.

Database Designer

Associate's Capstone February 2020

- DFGH
- Dfgh

•

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

Udacity Online

Data Analyst Nanodegree U

April 2023 - October 2023

- dfghjklkjhgf
- dfghjklkjhgf
- hgfghjk
- kjhgfghjk
- jhgfghjkl
- ;lkjhghjkl;

CIW

Data Analyst www February 2023

- Kjhgfghjkl;
- dfghjkl

ITIL4

IT Service Management Certification Quart

December 2022

- kjhgfghjkl
- fghjkl

CompTIA

Project+ Certificate

November 2022

- kjhgfdfghjkl;
- fghjklkjhgfd

CompTIA

Network+ Certificate

September 2022

- lkjhgfghjkl;
- dfghjkjhgfd

CompTIA

A+ Certificate

September 2022

- dfghjkjhgfd
- dfghjhgfdfgh

CISCO

Cybersecurity Essentials Certificate

August 2019

- Ikjhgfghjkl;
- dfghjkjhgf

CISCO

Networking Essentials Certificate

August 2019

- Ikjhgfghjkl;'
- fghjklkjhgf

HONORS & INVOLVEMENT

National Society of Leadership and Success

Foundations of Leadership Certificate

06/04/2021

oiuytfdfghjkl;

Phi Theta Kappa

Beta Nu Epsilon Chapter

Winterville, NC

• Eligibility, essays, received the WGU Phi Theta Kappa Scholarship.

04/16/2020

Gamma Beta Phi

Pitt Community College

Winterville, NC

Eligibility.

05/26/2019